# **Vincent Bundage II**

 ♀ Salt Lake City, UT
 ▼ vincentbundage@gmail.com
 ▼ vbundage.dev
 ♀ vbundage

### **PROFILE**

I am a software engineer based in Salt Lake City, Utah. I have several years of experience in full-stack engineering using JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang (Go), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS, GCP, Docker, and React. I co-created Pilot, an open-source multi-cloud framework that provisions an internal PaaS for deploying applications.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Co-Creator & Software Engineer,** *Pilot* 🖸

2021 - present

https://pilotframework.com/

- Designed, prototyped, and built Pilot using Node.js, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, Terraform, and Waypoint
- Implemented a Docker server to execute image builds and pushes from containers
- Contributed to automating AWS infrastructure deployment and teardown of Pilot server resources
- Led creation of Pilot's Waypoint Docker image to handle custom plugins and dependencies
- Researched and developed custom Waypoint plugins utilizing Go and gRPC protocol buffers
- Worked with AWS and GCP SDKs alongside gcloud to facilitate custom plugin operations to automate the deployment of front-end assets on either cloud provider's CDN solution
- Designed and implemented an Amazon RDS instance for connecting AWS deployed applications to a Postgres database using subnets and routing tables
- Contributed to CLI tool for Pilot setup, configuration, application deployment, SSH access, and teardown.
- Led manual testing of internal PaaS components and lifecycle of deploying applications to ensure expected functionality
- Troubleshooted issues impacting application deployments by malicious actors and prevented with a security group
  or firewall rule
- Co-authored a technical case study (https://pilotframework.com/case-study.html) exploring Pilot's design decisions, challenges, and architecture

# **Application Support Engineer, Netflix**

2019 - 2020

- Led product improvements by gathering user stories and pain points documented through Jira and escalation with Senior DevOps Engineers, Senior Product Reliability Engineers, and Senior Software Engineers.
- Tested, documented, and performed root cause analysis on issues in web applications pertaining to video encoding, dubbing, artwork assets, and content deployments.
- Participated in outage handling, messaging to end-users, and incident management

### **Software Engineer,** *Self-Employed*

2019 - 2021

- SpecBin: Generates endpoints for receiving and analyzing webhooks. Deployed on a DigitalOcean droplet behind Nginx. (React, Node/Express, Redis)
- Mello: Trello clone to create Kanban boards for collaboration. (React/Redux, Node/Express, MongoDB, Mongoose)
- Airlines: Display airline routes using sample data with filter functionality. (JavaScript, React)

# **SKILLS**

# Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, SQL, HTML, CSS

# **Technologies**

Docker, Git/GitHub, HTTP, REST APIs, Cloud Native Buildpacks, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Terraform, Waypoint, Jira, Confluence, VMWare

### Frameworks

Express, React/Redux, Node, Handlebars, Pug, jQuery

### **Cloud Technologies**

ECS, ECR, S3, IAM, VPC, ALB, EC2, CloudFront, RDS, Cloud Run, Google Cloud Storage, Container Registry, Cloud CDN, Compute Engine, Cloud SQL, Heroku, DigitalOcean

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Information Storage and Management ☑
- Implementation Engineer, Dell EMC Unity ☑
- VMware vSphere 6.7 Foundations

### **EDUCATION**